okay I'm just gonna welcome to the
stream mr. John Kiriakou and hi John can
you hear me
there he is hell why are you I am so
happy to see you thank you so much for
being here we're happy to do it
oh absolutely fabulous we've had so many
people so excited that you're gonna be
here oh my pleasure
John and we've just been doing a little
bit of an intro over the last hour or so
just explaining to people who's gonna be
or who are gonna be on the stream but
also what the understanding and founding
purpose of this is for us which is that
we have brought together people from
right across the political sphere with
completely different political opinions
and affiliations because we are united
in this one single purpose of advocating
for the human rights the protection and
restoration of the human rights of
Julian Assange demanding his freedom
that he'd be allowed to realize his
asylum in Ecuador and also recognizing
the the threat to Julian and WikiLeaks
as a grave threat to press freedom so
I'd really like you to talk to us about
those issues tonight because you are a
whistleblower and whistleblowers are
dependent upon journalists to get their
messages out is that correct oh it's
absolutely correct you know especially
in the intelligence community here in
the United States we're taught when
we're first hired that if you see
evidence of waste fraud abuse or
illegality that you go through the chain
of command but time and time again it's
been proven that that just simply
doesn't work Tom Drake went through the
chain of command he was rewarded with
nine felony charges including seven
counts of espionage bill bini Kirk Wiebe
Diane Roark went through their chains of
command and and they were arrested and
harassed by the police I didn't go
through my chain of command because my
chain of command created the CIA's
torture program I went to the press and
so really
for me the only thing to do is to go to
the press would be whistleblowers email
me call me call me all the time I get
this all the time and people ask me who
in the media should they go to well
outlets like the New York Times The
Washington Post the intercept have
encryption keys on their websites I
don't trust any of them frankly and I
tell people every time I'm asked the
only place to go is WikiLeaks because
WikiLeaks is the only organization that
has never blown a source it's the only
organization you can trust to handle
this kind of information and it that was
true years ago with Chelsea Manning it's
true today
you
absolutely an amazing point okay so then
conversely John what is the three you
know if we if we failed stand up for
Gillian we Faust in a for WikiLeaks I
mean what is the wider impact of that
the wider impact is that there's
literally nowhere for a whistleblower to
go and so the information just doesn't
get out I can't tell you how many times
people have said to me that that they
just assess that it's not worth going
forward so they just keep their mouth
shut and you know the the country is is
lesser for it here in the United States
especially with national security
whistleblowers I believe very firmly
that the American people own that
information the information belongs to
the people the citizens of the United
States not to the people who classified
it it's also illegal in the United
States to classify something that is a
crime it's illegal to classify something
so that it doesn't see the light of day
so that it can't go public well that
still happens every day and the only
reason we know about it is because of
whistleblowers well if there's no outlet
for a whistleblower to go to then the
information never goes public and then
we don't know what our government is
doing in our name and we have a right
it's and to me it's one of the most
important rights that that an American
can have the right to know what his
government is doing in his name
you
sorry I think we're getting a lot of
feedback from people that they're
finding it really powerful that we are
recognizing that this isn't a lift or a
right issue but this is a human a human
rights issue tar oh my goodness yes this
is not at all an issue of left or right
this is specific to human rights civil
rights and civil liberties and and it's
not specific to the United States
certainly this is this is an
international issue I think we're headed
toward an international crisis if we
turn our backs on Julian Assange I know
what it's like to feel like you're
standing alone to feel like the entire
weight of the government is has fallen
on your head that there's nowhere to
turn there's nowhere to go I know
exactly what the man is going through
and it's terrible it's lonely and so
it's up to us to remind him and to
remind the world the broader audience
out there that we're with him that we
support him we support the organization
and we support the issue and that we
won't back down as so many people here
in the US have been cowed by these
ridiculous comments by senior US
government officials that WikiLeaks is
akin to a hostile foreign intelligence
service well the reason that they've
said that is because they're afraid of
it and they're afraid of the work that
WikiLeaks has done they're afraid
because WikiLeaks has been effective
let's compare WikiLeaks to the the
intercept for example I'm biased against
the intercept because two of the two of
the journalists there were I'll just say
it straight out they were responsible
for putting me in prison for two years
because they blew my identity to the
government blatantly they did the same
thing to reality winner they may have
done the same thing to this FBI agent
who came forward in Minneapolis
Minnesota
you can't trust a national security
journalist if that national security
journalist doesn't know how to protect
his national security services
I'm sorry sources but look at WikiLeaks
WikiLeaks has never blown a
national-security source never and
beyond protecting the sources identity
they have protected the sources in the
documents that they've released and
that's why this process takes time
because they're going through these
documents to make sure that nobody gets
in trouble that nobody's identity is
compromised
no no journalism outlet does anything
like that that's specific to WikiLeaks
that's such an important point and
there's I mean and you have such with
all that said you have such a unique
perspective on on what is going on now
on the Julian situation and the
prosecution of him so um I was wondering
what your perspective is right now on
the current situation as its developed
especially sit during the time between
the first vigil and what we discussed
then and now like what what do you see
because you definitely have a very very
unique lens on this I stay current on
these issues day to day and I'll tell
you the honest to goodness truth is I'm
worried and I'm worried for a couple of
reasons first of all when Julian had his
internet access suspended and his
visitors suspended I don't know why but
I believe this to be a temporary
situation I thought okay they're trying
to make a point
a week later though they'll loosen
things up again and they haven't besides
that and and this is what worries me
even more I delivered a letter to the
Ecuadorian ambassador to the United
States a few months ago asking the
ambassador to ask his government to to
let Julian have internet access the very
next day an article appeared in The Wall
Street Journal and it was entitled
Ecuador is open for business
and it talked about how the Ecuadorian
government had approached the Trump
administration to try to improve and to
enhance business ties that sent a chill
up my spine because it made me think and
fear that Julian may be used as a pawn
so the Ecuadorian gun
can make a little bit of money so that
troubles me very deeply and that's not
something I was worried about just a few
short months ago
definitely it's an absolutely terrifying
prospect that he might be used as
leverage in that way and that this
suffering could be leveraged really
really disturbing let me interrupt you
too I want to talk about some rumors
here in one absolutely the rumor is that
either Julian has been indicted in the
Eastern District of Virginia or that a
grand jury has been impaneled in the
Eastern District of Virginia the reason
why this would be done in the Eastern
District rather than in Washington DC or
any in any other district in the country
is that the Eastern District of Virginia
is known as the espionage Court no
national security defendant has ever won
a case there ever
I was tried their head Snowden was
charged there Jeffrey sterling was
charged there we've all had our cases in
the Eastern District of Virginia there's
one judge in particular judge Leonie
brinkema who reserves all of these cases
for herself so she's been the judge for
all of us and we were all found guilty
beyond that she made it literally
impossible to mount a defense because
every time we would motion the court to
allow us to declassify information
necessary to defend ourselves
she denied the motion she denied seventy
two of my motions and have proved zero
we were walking out of the courtroom one
day and I said to my attorney what just
happened and my attorney said we just
lost the case that's what happened well
Julian is looking at the same kind of
outcome if he's forced out of that
Embassy and extradited to the United
States he will not he cannot get a fair
trial it's impossible because the deck
is stacked and everybody knows what's
going to happen if he comes back to the
Eastern District of Virginia this is the
same advice I gave that Snowden don't
come home because you can't get a fair
trial here Julian doesn't have the
choice and that's what frightens me even
more yeah not so important to here
from you from your perspective on that I
think that's a really important
information for our audience to have
about what it is exactly that he faces
if he were to lose asylum or to walk out
of the embassy this would not be a fair
judicial process whatsoever so you know
thank you for explaining that oh sure
and we also have to remember that that
the the Brits are essentially puppets of
the United States in cases like this
they they will do anything that the US
intelligence community tells them to do
and I think we can all assume should
assume that the US has told the British
that as soon as Julian walks out of that
embassy that the US wants him yeah and I
believe recently after the first vigil
Cassandra actually tweeted an old leaked
picture of the orders that the police
guarding the embassy were given which
was to immediately arrest him
immediately put him into custody if he
came out even if he was somehow in I
believe the the document said that if he
was in a diplomatic bag or something
ridiculous like that but basically there
this is not a normal you know process
that he's going through and it would not
be a normal result if he would leave so
no certainly not and his hands are tied
you know up until now I think all of us
believe that we could count on the
Ecuadorians I hope that we still can I
know that I know that President Correa
has expect for mer President Correa has
expressed disappointment in in lynnie
Moreno's policy toward Julian I still
hope that this policy is temporary I
know we all do definitely I hope so as
well I hope that with voices like yours
and all of the other voices that are
being raised whether it's you know Roger
Waters you know with this concert all of
these efforts I hope that that will make
a real difference for Moreno and his
decision on this do to John that point
that you just brought up before about
how the last time we got together for
the first virtual event you were
confident or you felt sure that Julian's
communications will be restored I think
I felt exactly the same way and the
reason that we actually designed unity
for Jay is in
a new mass movement and not just a
continuation of how I connect Julian is
because we actually thought to ourselves
oh yeah he'll be reconnected any day now
but the larger issues that we need to
free him from the embassy and we also we
just took it for granted that because
previously had been disconnected and
then reconnected that it was just a
matter of time but looking at you know
the geopolitical situation and seeing as
you're just talking about Ecuador in the
the developments with linen merino it
seems that we might have I think there's
a it's a human tendency actually you
know we look at someone like Julian who
goes through so much who faces such vast
incredible forces and he seems to just
you know weather weather every storm and
take almost take it on the chin but we
know in reality is not in reality he is
suffering severely his serious medical
conditions there's the his situation is
far more dire than you would know by
reading the mainstream media you know
and I'm thinking like how dangerous it
is that we would just take for granted
that he'd be reconnected and and that
seems like a huge danger to me yeah this
is a list of urgency we need to there is
an emergency that's right this is a
lesson that we we shouldn't take
anything for granted
at this point and you raised a very
important point too this is a human
rights issue relative to his health and
this is something that really is not
reported anywhere but the man's health
cannot be very good closed up in that
embassy 24 hours a day seven days a week
he needs sunlight he needs exercise he
needs nutritious food and we have no
idea if he's getting any of that
you
well fortunately we do know that he said
that they're feeding him but there was
probably the most alarming statement
I've ever heard was out of one of his
legal team a few weeks ago who's
actually said there you know he faces
not even being able to see down the
hallway because his eyesight is
degrading so severely from only having
this tiny limited space he's he's
actually suffering organ damage and I
know from studying his medical reports
that his doctors have said that he's a
mortal risk
it's no joke he is literally at mortal
growth risk so how do we how do we
convince people of this how do we
humanize him John you know I think we
have to keep doing what we're doing and
we have to keep reminding everybody that
this is a human rights issue you know
the the mainstream media tends to not
cover Julian's story there might be an
update of a few sentences every once in
a while saying Julian Assange is still
in the Ecuadorian Embassy we need to
make sure that it's out there all the
time even if that's just in the
mainstream media for the time being I
have a I have a small radio show in in
Washington and we talk about Julian all
the time we interview people like Danny
burrito and and Randy credito for
example people who know Julian and have
seen him and have spoken to him because
we need that first-hand accounting of
his health and his spirits and any news
that he may have for us anything that he
has heard perhaps from the Ecuadorians
perhaps from his attorneys we need to
make sure that the information is out
there and people are reminded every day
that this is a very important issue and
it's very dangerous for Julian Assange
absolutely we did we did recently see a
series of pieces come out of the
Guardian it was the typical smear pieces
but at this time it was an entire series
of them and interestingly they were
based on anonymous sources but those
anonymous sources were leaking
information about intelligence agency
activities and there had been actually
in defense of Julian providing security
to the embassy what's your take on that
John where it seems that leaking
information to the press is fine if
you're doing it to attack a
whistleblower rather than to be a
whistleblower Oh welcome to my life you
know the the biggest leakers in
Washington are the White House the CIA
and the FBI that's been a fact of life
since the creation of those
organizations because this is what they
do they do it to control the story they
do it to control the debate they do it
to influence public opinion it's it's
only a leak if it's something that they
don't like if it's something that they
like it's authorized we see the same
thing with the Guardian and I have to
add to I've been very disappointed in
the Guardian you know the Guardian was
one of the recipients of of Julian's
largesse of information directly from
from WikiLeaks and to turn on him like
they have and what's supposed to be a
progressive paper is really very very
disappointing
I completely agree and that that uh
escalation of those six you know
articles on him was really shocking to
see I mean it was really seemed like
they were just piling on and accusing
him of stuff that was absolutely
ludicrous and I thought it was great we
saw WikiLeaks actually well yeah like
say that they were going to file a suit
for libel because it was so ridiculous
sorry agreed and what do you think that
that signifies that we see those pylons
like that do you think that that's
because you know from their perspective
they had to you know undo some of the
successful backlash this this gagging of
him which has as I said it's become a
backlash in terms of increasing support
for him do you think that was the main
the main goal with that or was it more
to yes we also have to remember that
intelligence services all around the
world are are well schooled in
psychological warfare and I think that
this is this is a concerted attempt a
formal attempt to to weaken Julian
mentally emotionally maybe even
physically and to to make him give up in
the end I think that's really the goal
you know they they can plant stories and
whatever media they want they put these
false narratives out there and people
are gullible they'll believe anything
they read in the press with the ultimate
result being Julian's weakening yeah I
think we can truly blame intelligence
services for this and be right John I'd
like you to game theory a little bit for
me um I think you can take the this
collaboration of intelligence services
with the Guardian and smearing Julian
Assange you could take it two ways
one is that the u.s. is now really on
top of the situation and they're like
this far away from getting their hands
on Julian and they're winning the media
war that there could be true or it could
be and this is what I suspect that they
are trying to depict that that is the
case and that they are hoping that by
depicting them
as being in this position of incredible
strength and ecuador is collaborating
with them that they will be able to you
know manifest the future that they that
they want to realize rather than their
actually being the situation what does
he take on that what is the the second
scenario is entirely plausible and the
the reason why I believe that it could
be the case that you never hear any any
complaints really about WikiLeaks coming
out of the White House you remember
during the campaign Donald Trump said I
love WikiLeaks remember that I mean he
was he was grandstanding of course but
slowly definitely yeah well so we're not
seeing leaks coming from the Justice
Department we're not seeing leaks coming
from the White House the only things
that we're seeing are coming from the
FBI and the CIA and then we're seeing
actually public statements from former
CIA director Mike Pompeo so there may be
a policies lid here that this is this is
a tier one target or operation for the
CIA but it's really not very important
for the White House so your second
scenario may very well be the case but
again either way regardless of whether
it's the first scenario or the second
one of the goals is to weaken Julian and
to isolate Julian and that's what we
really have to push back on and we
really don't have much in the way of
ammunition except papal power exactly
because we know that international law
is on Julian side we know the president
is on Julian side he has one time and
time again in his legal battles against
the government's and I kind of say
agencies that really governments there
that are persecuting him and that
arbitrarily detaining him I think what
is going to have to happen is he's going
to have to be a mass movement an
international movement a la free Nelson
Mandela movement of the 80s to push it
you know to turn the tide to put enough
pressure on these governments that they
will have to abide by international law
and that they will have to free him John
I'd like to take you back in time a
little bit actually
like you to take us back in time a
little bit from my perspective you are a
hero you're a celebrated whistleblower
your whistle blowing was of historic
proportions as I was saying earlier and
when I was discussing the fact you'd be
on stream your revelations made a US
president have to stand up and answer to
what was being done and there are very
few people on this planet that can say
that they've had that type of impact on
global affairs he said that you just
just a moment ago though you were
talking about feeling isolated and
feeling like the world was against you
and so I wondered can you take us back
in time to explain to us tell us the
story of that transition how did you get
from point a of being all by yourself on
your lonesome against the most fearsome
Intelligence Agency in the world
arguably to being a household name and
celebrated as a hero and having your
whistleblowing recognized at the level
that it has been well on the on the day
that the FBI told me that they were
going to arrest me
they actually intended to arrest me that
day and the only thing that saved me was
I said I want to speak to my lawyer and
I want to speak to him right now that
was on a Thursday the FBI likes to
arrest people on Thursdays because the
courts don't arraign new prisoners on
Fridays and so you have to spend
Thursday night Friday night Saturday
night and Sunday night in jail and
frankly they hope that you have a rough
time maybe you get beaten up it softens
you up a little bit and then you're more
willing to take a deal I'm not
exaggerating when I tell you that every
whistleblower who's facing prison
considers suicide it's just a natural
thing I've spoken to 50 different
whistleblowers and to a man and woman
every one of them considered committing
suicide in the very beginning it's that
terrible it's that difficult you really
feel that isolated but there were two
things that kind of
changed my perspective one was my wife
she told me a couple of days after my
arraignment on the following Monday they
have consistently underestimated your
strength you can you can take them she
said you have to fight them and she was
right I had to fight and I decided that
I would she also said that I had to own
my whistle blowing that I had done
nothing to be ashamed of I had done
something instead to be proud of and
that if I kept talking about it
eventually my side of the story would
become the side of record and the
government's story would disappear after
a while because they would move on to
their next victim who happened to be Ed
Snowden and so I did keep talking about
it now when I first went to prison I was
just you know prisoner number 7 9 6 8 3
o 8 3 I wasn't anybody and then I wrote
a letter an open letter to my attorneys
six weeks after I got to prison just to
tell them what the experience was like
up to that point I didn't even realize
that I was blowing the whistle on on
corruption inside the prison the prison
guards corruption it led to an inspector
general investigation in the Department
of Justice and my attorney sent it to
Arianna Huffington she put it on the
Huffington Post and it got more than a
million hits which was a real surprise
to me I I was I was getting interview
requests from everywhere from CNN and
Fox and and MSNBC and Time magazine The
Washington Post the New York Times it
was crazy about six weeks after that Ed
Snowden went public with his revelations
and I wrote an open letter to him and I
followed it up with a private letter
that I sent through him you to a friend
the open letter received many millions
of hits and I realized then so it took
me a good six months I realized then
that I wasn't alone that there were a
lot of like-minded people out there I
just didn't realize it and
people started writing to me and I made
a decision on my very first day in
prison that if somebody was going to
take time out of their day to sit with a
pen and paper and write me a letter I
was going to answer that letter and I
ended up answering more than 7,000
letters in the 23 months that I was in
prison and again every letter that I
received was a reminder that I was not
alone that we were in this together and
you know we had a chance at success
because this was a real movement that is
absolutely incredible and I think it's
really really helpful for the audience
to hear that they've made such a
difference to receive those letters yeah
I think that that is really important
for people to understand and apply the
same to Julianne in this situation right
now
I agree write those letters it only
takes a few minutes just a few minutes
you can imagine how much that'll bright
is brighten his day when he receives it
and knows that he's not alone absolutely
because yeah he wasn't he's not just
confined now to the embassy as we know
he's obviously in actually a solitary
confinement style situation so yeah you
know what because that's exactly what
this is this is solitary confinement you
know the United Nations has declared
solitary confinement as a form of
torture absolutely
solitary confinement just because he
happens to have a television doesn't
make it any less confining so this is
something that we need to to remember
the solitary confinement in part is
meant to break you mentally and I don't
care how tough you are or how strong you
are everybody is going to break
eventually
so our letters are gonna help keep him
steady and sane and focused it's up to
us to make sure that he's not forgotten
the human the human link there is so so
incredibly important and I it's
interesting that Suzy was mentioning
that this has to be a movement for that
similar to the Nelson Mandela movement
in the 80s in fact the UN's our
regulations and rules on solitary
confinement are named for Nelson Mandela
they're called the Nelson Mandela rules
and I mean we know that Assange is going
into his third month in in this
situation and
the limit the limit beyond which it's
considered torture it's 15 days so he is
more than quadrupled that and in
addition that yeah the medical records
that Susie mentioned earlier also showed
that he was already exhibiting effects
of solitary confinement medically in
2015 years before this new isolation was
implemented so I mean I couldn't agree
with you more about this whole the whole
issue of solitary confinement and the
importance of the connection remaining
there in some way agreed this is this is
potentially grave we all need to be
worried about this I think that
sometimes I think in in American culture
and in the public space we think of
torture and we think of something active
and physical happening to somebody you
know that's this graphic and terrible
and that that's true but we don't we
underestimate how incredibly painful and
how concretely isolation affects people
physically and biologically and you said
just as you said um everyone will break
at some point that is so true and that's
backed up in medical literature it shows
that isolation absolutely causes brain
changes it causes all sorts of medical
issues so this situation as you've said
cannot be underestimated at the CIA they
called it learned helplessness and
that's exactly what it is you just
accept the fact that you're helpless and
there's nothing that you can do that's
going to help you you can't help
yourself and so you just fall apart and
I think that's what they're counting on
absolutely and I think that you know as
you said I think people sometimes
hesitate to write letters because they
think oh what can I say of importance or
they think well will this even get
through and I think that if you have
that type of hesitation please just
write it anyway
even if they're all thrown out if you
are writing those letters you are making
an act that you are enacting you know
something that will really truly help
really and survive this you know as john
saying where his lifeline right now so
don't underestimate your own actions
there were so many people who wrote to
me just about their day you know how
their day was one woman you know visited
her daughter one woman wrote to me and
explained this new car
game that she had learned a woman would
take pictures of birds that landed in
her backyard and send me the pictures I
can't tell you how wonderful that was
because you know for even just a few
minutes you forget that you're in a cage
and that you're being held under armed
guard it's surrounded by barbed wire
fences and guard towers it's liberating
even just for a few minutes so don't
worry about about trying to think up
something profound just just say hello
and tell him how your day is that's
incredible to hear I think that's really
important for people to hear because I
know that a lot of people as Suzy was
saying earlier they don't see us on jazz
as a human being like the rest of us
they see it as somebody who's kind of up
on a pedestal almost and we really have
to understand that he is a human being
and he needs connection to other human
beings in order to survive because we
all do so that's right definitely so I'm
gonna check chat really fast and see if
we have any questions for you that are
in the in that chat one moment why look
if you guys have questions for John
please let us know and we will pass
those on immediately I'm really
interested to know how how are you
yourself because you're also in that
same kind of position where you lord it
as a hero by so so many people they look
up to you so much what you've done but
at the end of the day you know that you
I yourself you're a normal guy who got a
family you got a normal life you deal
with the everyday today struggles of you
know every person on the planet how do
you have you felt that disconnect
between the way that you depicted the
image of you versus your reality oh yeah
most definitely
I'm just a guy I'm just a normal guy
there's nothing special about me in any
way you know and I'm subject to the same
kind of pressures that everybody else
has maybe more because with my
conviction for example I lost my federal
pension and so I'm gonna have to work
until the day I die that's just a
reality Daniel Ellsberg told me one
thing one time that one thing that all
whistleblowers have in common is that
they die broke that they're never able
to make a financial comeback after there
was
blowing I I'm determined that that won't
be me but you know as the years begin to
tick by since I first went public I'm
realizing that that may be me
so yeah I don't see myself as anything
special
frankly I tried to not blow the whistle
I kept waiting for someone else to come
forward and nobody did so I finally said
something Wow you know who said that
word for word
Snowden that's very true that's a very
very very true yeah and the cost is very
very high you know it's not just
financial but personal to my wife
finally had enough and and she walked
and I can't blame her this dress is
terrible the pressure is unbearable
sometimes so yeah there's the
counterbalance to that like on one on
one side we have the price of the risk
so that we take the price that we pay
the horrific price that we pay but on
the other side of that as Snowden says
you can look yourself in the mirror I
say that every day I'll tell you four
days before I left for prison Jose
Rodriguez the the the godfather of the
CIA's torture program the deputy
director of the CIA tweeted at me and he
said don't drop the soap [__] and I
gave myself an hour to cool off and then
I tweeted back at him and I said Jose
I'm on the right side of history and you
are not and I left it at that and I know
all these years later that I was right I
was right and he was wrong
I know I can sleep at night so it was
worth it
that is so important to recognize and
it's really horrific how those types of
people that are so high up in the
intelligence community will take these
really like personal and ad hominem
attacks at not just yourself and not
just whistleblowers like Chelsea Manning
but also of course Julian Assange and
WikiLeaks it's really it's really it
really reveals their true nature I think
when we see it it really does there are
a lot of sociopaths walking around yeah
definitely I think that it's interesting
cuz I was just contemplating this today
actually about a certain CIA ex-cia now
state official who I won't mention but I
was actually contemplating this very
effective which is that in their day to
day life they have all other cushy perks
of having sold this all to the devil
they have the nice suits they have the
big pay Packers they have the safety of
knowing that they're not going to be
stalked and spied on and targeted and
smeared but when they go home at night
and they have to look themselves in the
mirror
on some level I believe that they are
conscious that their power is derived
from the this apparatus that oppresses
and that destroys our planet it's not
they don't have any personal power
the only power they have in their life
comes from has been given them to them
or granted from them selling out to the
system they're selling them solar system
we're as whistleblowers and some
journalists are the opposite of that in
their day to day lives they don't have
the power
other than that they can derive from
their own speech and their own
self-worth they don't have the trappings
of power they don't that you know they
have to face the smears and the
hardships and as you say like the
financial ruin but then at night time
they can look themselves in the mirror
and they know that they didn't sell out
to the system they didn't they are not
participating in the destruction of the
planet that and I was very much
contemplating that today because we
think
these and people as these big scary
figures the CIA you know top CIA
officials and whatnot but it's the
system that holds the power it's not
those people as individuals if anything
those people as individuals have sold
out their ability to have any personal
power to become an agent and Agent Smith
of the state and am i under some of your
laughing John so I must be onto
something you're really onto something
that's that's quite true a senior CIA
former senior CIA official told me just
last week he's been retired for I don't
know a year a year and a half he told me
that he had to go on an antidepressant
medication because on Friday he was one
of the most important people in America
and on Monday he was a nobody because he
had retired and he can't handle being a
nobody and so he's been struggling with
such profound depression that he has to
be medicated Wow
that's a theme at the CIA they all think
that they're the most important people
in America because they they have they
have sort of self-appointed jurisdiction
over life and death for so many people
and then they trick themselves into
thinking that they're irreplaceable and
in fact they're very replaceable
absolutely yeah the the groupthink that
goes on in the intelligence agencies
that can be so intense i i've read you
know in different different press
reports that it's so intense that it
actually damages their ability to
function and in some instances is that
something that you have seen or
absolutely in fact one of my attorneys
bruce fine and i have been talking about
writing a book exactly about that
because if you look at it at the the
major international developments over
the last 70 years since the creation of
the CIA the CIA has been wrong about
just about every one of them and it's
it's because of that groupthink you know
they throw around these these these
slogans and and business buzzwords about
thinking outside the box and
establishing a red team or a
your team and it's all nonsense they
don't know what they're doing
in fact they end up sitting around a
conference room table and just agreeing
with one another that's incredible
that's amazing to hear like it's from
somebody who's really experienced it
that's really really interesting
thank you for sure just just just back
to the psyche issues thing it just
reminds me of the WikiLeaks group and
I'm sure that this is going to be one of
the reasons the CIA really has it in for
them WikiLeaks publishing the leaked
Brennan emails from his mount or comet
race and in there was sure enough was
his psych reports from his he'd actually
been seeing a psychologist to deal with
the emotional fallout of being a
tyrannical CIA director so funny isn't
it you know CIA psychiatrist once told
me that the CIA and I say this is my
speeches all the time the CIA actively
seeks to hire people who have
sociopathic tendencies they try not to
hire sociopaths
because sociopaths have no conscience
and with no conscience they easily pass
a polygraph exam but they're impossible
to control because they don't feel guilt
people who have sociopathic tendencies
do have a conscience and do feel guilt
but are happy to work in moral ethical
and legal gray areas the problem is that
because sociopaths are sociopaths
they're gonna slip through the cracks
anyway and like in any corporate
environment it's the sociopaths who work
their way to the top and they work their
way to the top because they're all so
happy to just climb over the backs of
their colleagues and co-workers to make
it to the top and that's how you end up
with a John Brennan or a Jose Rodriguez
or a George Tenet because they actually
are sociopaths well that makes it much
sense
go Ahead's easy but then even these
sociopaths there that are involved in so
much selecting so much pain and on this
entire planet as well as people on it
they still seem to have at some level
this deeps
illogical fallout and I find that quite
fascinating because it tells me that
even though they condition to exhibiting
this psychopathic behavior at some level
I truly think that deep down in a little
box somewhere that they keep it hidden
then is this tiny scrap of conscience
well I personally disagree with that
completely but that's just my personal
take on that I think there are people
that are biologically different than
other people in that way but Oh step out
of that I hope Suzie's right I don't
know to tell you the truth but it seems
to me that that any normal person I mean
you can only kill so many people or be
responsible for the deaths of so many
people before something gets to you I
mean you've got to end up with with PTSD
or some kind of psychological malady
you can't just unless you're a true
sociopath and then you can just kill
with impunity and and go right to sleep
at night this is just I'm just bringing
this back to Julianna's maybe this
discussion is making me reflect on the
fact that the CIA derives its power from
its ability to inflict violence and to
control people and Julian Assange has
derived his power from his ability to
save people for his ability to provide
them with the truth
the CIA derives power from lies from
their false Flags and their fate color
revolutions and their everything else
Julian and WikiLeaks have derived power
from truth-telling and that's why there
are such a threat because if there's one
thing that the CIA cannot abide that is
transparency there it makes so much
sense
this that's the house of cards right
mm-hmm
exactly it can bring down the house of
cards amazing
that also reminds me while we're getting
into like theory of stuff it reminds me
of a diagram that I saw it was a
counterinsurgency doctrine and it said
it's like the three pillars of society
and when was the financial one was the
police and one was the government and
these three pillars in a house formation
and on the bottom the foundation of the
house is information and information was
the only factor that had the capacity to
bring down all three pillars and they
said that each pillar on its own could
fall and the structure could remain so
you could have a total financial crash
but the police state the security stayed
in military and the government combined
would keep the house up you could have
you know lose your military force but
still the financial and the government
is enough to like rebuild that as we've
seen in many states that have had to
rebuild their security forces we could
have a you lose the Prime Minister the
Prime Minister has to sit down the
government is dissolved but you still
have the police of military security
state and you still have the financial
role that the house stays up but the
information pool at the bottom when you
threaten that information pool you place
all three pillars in jeopardy and that
was the counterinsurgency doctrine oh I
believe every word of that I think
that's exactly right and years and years
of thought have gone into that doctrine
they know exactly what they're talking
about but again we have this leg in yang
where the CIA would use that doctrine to
destabilize a country they would use
information warfare to destabilize those
three pillars that are holding their
society together WikiLeaks is using
information to destabilize those who
would destabilize the society if that
makes sense here it's like they they are
almost like the inoculating force
WikiLeaks is like the inoculating force
to the virus absolutely right and that's
why we need WikiLeaks because because
there are no journalistic outlets that
have that
of power you know it only WikiLeaks does
the Washington Post isn't going to take
down the CIA whether the New York Times
or The Guardian or the intercept only
WikiLeaks has that kind of authority and
leverage that's why we need a strong
WikiLeaks and that's why we need a free
Julian Assange exactly they're the
integrity that nobody else has nobody at
all so from your perspective how do
people what is some of the what are some
of the ways and I mean you know I know
we've hashed this up before but from
your unique perspective how can people
that are listening and watching you know
actively help you know help support
WikiLeaks and Julian Assange you know in
addition to the letter writing to keep
him you know connected to humanity what
are some of the things people can really
tangibly do to help that you that you
think of from what he done through I was
speaking to a member of Congress about a
week ago and the topic of WikiLeaks came
up and this guy is a very conservative
Republican he's a member of the tea
party caucus here in the States which is
the it's a group of the most
conservative members of the House of
Representatives and he said that he had
sort of a knee-jerk reaction against
WikiLeaks for a long time until
constituents began to write to him and
to ask arresting for WikiLeaks
and so he said he never really gave it
much thought until people began to write
and you know these guys really are
responsive to their constituents they
really are I've worked on both the house
side and the Senate side and I can tell
you that when people write letters to
their elected representatives they
listen and so he actually reevaluated
and reinstate reassessed his entire
position on WikiLeaks I'm not sure that
he's willing to say that publicly yet
but you know one at a time and over time
we can actually win this thing I think
that's a really really valuable piece of
information for people to have because I
know that when I give that answer to
people well you can write letters to
your representatives you can write
letters to so-and-so you know there's
kind of that sense of like well that's
not enough and people have to understand
how
a real impact that makes it's a big deal
truly absolutely so is there anything
else you want to talk to us about about
your experience with Julian Assange or
WikiLeaks or anything else related to
this whole issue I just want to let
people understand oh go right ahead nor
my audio just cut out for a second I
thought it was hers and then I realized
it was mine I'm sorry girlfriend right I
just wanted to say that I'm genuinely
worried about Julian you know I before
they cut off his communication his
access to the outside world I wasn't
really worried about him and I thought
well you know eventually this thing is
going to play out and he's gonna end up
being fine and something's gonna happen
they're gonna drop the charges and
they're not gonna charge him in the
first place or the Brits are gonna walk
away or whatever I'm worried now I'm
worried because I really believed for a
long time that we could count on the
Ecuadorians and I'm not sure that's the
case anymore so I feel like there's a
sense of urgency or immediacy and we
need to we need to pull together and be
active now more than we ever have in the
past
I completely agree I think it's so
important to hear that I hear I
understand that message definitely I'm
from your perspective what was the most
significant I mean WikiLeaks has got
dozens of significant publications but
what was the only thing that if he you
was deeply personally significant yeah
you know in in the Snowden revelations
the the notion that that the American
government was spying on its own
citizens I think most people don't
understand the full significance of that
information the NSA and CIA are
forbidden by law from spying on
Americans NSA's Charter actually
prohibits it from spying on Americans
but that's exactly what they were doing
using 9/11 as an excuse
using the Patriot Act as a justification
it was only because of Snowden's
revelations that a the American people
became aware of what was happening and
be members of Congress began realizing
that this thing is starting to spin out
of control
and so it's just now in the last
year-and-a-half that Congress has begun
to reject certain provisions of the
Patriot Act they've just begun to weaken
parts of it so we're not we can't call
it a victory yet but we're headed in
that direction and that's only because
of Ed Snowden and WikiLeaks
I find it fascinating what you were just
saying that members of Congress actually
are responsive because I remember when
courage Foundation was urging supporters
of law read loved to reach out to
members of UK Parliament and I actually
thought to myself quite cynically you
know nothing gets the effort but I
thought to myself I will any of these
politicians even care you know what's
the chance of them like reading the
leaders and then sure enough courage was
able to drum up like some phenomenal
amount of impes wasn't it like 60 or 70
even some huge amount of politicians and
actually managed to get them to advocate
for Laurie and I think it very much was
a deciding factor in that case and the
successful outcome of Laurie's case you
know a dozen House members and two
senators wrote to the Bureau of Prisons
inquiring about my well-being and
threatening them to not put me in what
was called diesel therapy which was to
transfer me to different prisons around
the country to silence me and it was
only because people were writing letters
to their congressmen these congressmen
really are receptive they really are
reactive to it
that's amazing yeah go ahead well how do
we leverage that how do we would
leverage that for Jillian you know um
there's something to be said for a good
old-fashioned letter-writing campaign
they're they're important especially
especially if you're writing to people
who actually represent you for example I
live in Virginia if I write to a senator
from South Dakota he's not gonna care or
congressman from South Dakota but if
somebody from South Dakota writes
they're gonna jump to attention and I
can write to my representatives here in
Virginia and they will jump to attention
so if we've got a concerted nationwide
or semi nationwide campaign going we can
really get results that way you know
we've just had a question from the
YouTube live chat and they've said why
did Obama believe his legacy would be
enhanced by his commutation of Chelsea's
sentence and that is some kind of I
can't even say the word that
synchronizes with the thought that I was
just having which is remembering that
WikiLeaks had you just talking about the
power of a good old-fashioned letter
writing campaign that WikiLeaks actually
did leader writing campaigns to Obama on
with Chelsea Manning's behalf the years
before the eventual commutation so what
what would be your response to that
question about why why do you think that
Obama did go ahead and and commute the
sentence I actually know the answer from
inside Obama's head and I'll tell you
why a very wealthy Greek American
businessman who is very personally close
to Joe Biden approached Biden to ask him
if he would ask Obama to pardon me and
so I went to Delaware one night I took
the train and went to Biden's house and
this Greek American took the train down
from New York and we met at Biden's
house and Biden agreed to go to the
president the next night and lobby for
me so the next day the two of them went
to the White House I went home I wasn't
invited to the White House
and and when they came out the Greek
American businessman called me and he
said you would have been so proud of Joe
Biden he went to the mat for you he
argued your case with everything that he
had and then he said ten minutes into it
the president put up his hands and said
guys I'm just not going to do this it's
either him or it's Manning and Manning
got thirty five years and that's why
Obama did it Obama was not upset that
Chelsea was convicted Obama just
believed that 35 was too much so he
didn't really commute Chelsea's sentence
out of the goodness of his heart
or because of some some you know pursuit
of justice I mean we all know now that
Barack Obama was the enemy of
transparency he waged a war on
whistleblowers Chelsea just got lucky in
the end yeah that's something that a lot
of people underestimate and don't take
into account is how much Obama actually
escalated a lot of these problems
prosecute eight national security
whistleblowers that's almost three times
the number of all previous presidents
combined extremely just mind-boggling
that a supposedly liberal president
would do that type of thing and it
really kind of reveals that it's not
just you know it's not New York on one
side of the political spectrum this is
obviously an unelected power structure
that persists despite whoever is elected
president and that that's that's the
power that as you've been saying Julian
Assange is up against right now and that
is what is so disturbing and I think as
you mentioned that's what overrides the
fact you know whatever comments Trump
may have made on the campaign trail that
own alleged power structure has it has
its own agenda so yeah let me let me
leave you with one thought I know my
time is up it's not looking fine you're
gonna fine
I really do with one more thought
there's a pardon process a formal pardon
process here in the states it's both
pardon and commutation in brock obama's
final two years as president the u.s.
pardon attorney recommended zero people
for a partner zero the
commutations but nobody was pardoned in
the last two years so you know you're
right it doesn't matter if you're
liberal or conservative or neo liberal
or neo conservative it makes no
difference we have to elect people
regardless of party for whom civil
rights and civil liberties and human
rights are important
because the the the deep state or the
federal bureaucracy whatever you want to
call it isn't gonna do it for us that's
an incredibly important
you know statement and it's a great one
to leave everyone with thank you so much
for joining us thank you best of luck
tonight thank you it's an honor to speak
with you and happy here was all mine
thanks for inviting me thank you so much
John we are so so lucky to have you I
just want to thank you too from the
bottom my heart it's really special to
speak with you is amazing thank you so
much it's great to Julian absolutely
absolutely thank you